|

|

US English

*  US English
    
*  UK English
    
*  Español
    
*  Português

|

US English

*  US English
    
*  UK English
    
*  Español
    
*  Português

Log In Sign Up Now » Sign Up

Log In
------

Sign Up
-------

* 
    
    Need some help? [Contact Support](https://www.typing.com/support)

* Sign Up Now »

Select a product:

Privacy Policy
==============

Privacy Policy Updated: September 2024
--------------------------------------

Thank you for your interest in Typing.com! Please read the below privacy policy in detail. However, in plain English: Typing.com offers both a free (Student and Teacher), ad-supported version and a premium (Student and Teacher), subscription-based version. The personal information that we collect, use, share, and disclose is dependent upon the version utilized. **In either version, we do not share, sell, or otherwise give away private information or information that, by itself, can identify you as a specific individual!**

However, in the ad-supported version, certain aggregated and anonymized data is collected and used by third parties. There are many ways to opt-out of these data usages, which are detailed below, but the simplest is to purchase the premium version. Contact [\[email protected\]](https://www.typing.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) for more information.

Now, please enjoy the legalese:

Typing.com has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. This privacy policy applies to information, including personal information, that Typing.com (a product of Teaching.com) collects about you when you visit our website. This policy does not apply to other Teaching.com websites or apps.

While most of Typing.com is a general audience website through which we do not knowingly collect information from children under 13, the teacher portal portion of our site contains features for teachers (such as grading and reporting on performance) designed for students who may be Children.

Information Rights
------------------

This website is designed to comply with applicable privacy regulations, including the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), except as limited by applicable law. We acknowledge the importance of privacy regulations and assure you we have taken steps to comply with relevant laws, however, please note that user data is stored and processed outside the European Union. These are the rights we comply with under GDPR:

* **Access:** This includes your right to access the personal information we gather about you, and your right to obtain information about the sharing, storage, security, and processing of that information.
* **Correction:** This is your right to request correction of your personal information.
* **Erasure:** This is your right to request, subject to certain limitations under applicable law, that your personal information be erased from our possession (also known as the “Right to be forgotten”). However, if applicable law requires us to comply with your request to delete your information, fulfillment of your request may prevent you from using Typing.com services and may result in closing your account.
* **Complain:** You have the right to make a complaint regarding our handling of your personal information with the appropriate supervisory authority.
* **Restrict Processing:** This is your right to request restriction of how and why your personal information is used or processed.
* **Object:** This is your right, in certain situations, to object to how or why your personal information is processed.
* **Portability:** This is your right to receive the personal information we have about you and the right to transmit it to another party.
* **Automated Decision-Making:** This is your right to object and prevent any decision that could have a legal, or similarly significant, effect on you from being made solely based on automated processes. This right is limited, however, if the decision is necessary for the performance of any contract between you and us, is allowed by applicable European law, or is based on your explicit consent.

Information We Collect
----------------------

In both the free and paid versions of our site, we may collect information directly from users, from students, or from school officials.

In addition, the free version may use other tracking mechanisms to collect information from the users directly from the browsers.

We collect information from you directly when you establish an account with Typing.com. The following is the information collected, processed, and stored through our websites.

When you create an account on our Websites, we may collect the following information:

* **Basic Account Information for Teacher/Administrator Account Holders:** You may establish a teacher/administrator account with Typing.com by providing us with certain information about you, such as: name, email address, school or district affiliation, country, and role.
* **Basic Account Information for Student Account Holders:** You may establish a student account with Typing.com by providing us with a username and password, and optionally, an email address.

Typing.com collects and processes this basic account information in order to provide you with an account, access to the Services, and (if an email address is provided) communicate with you regarding our Services.

**Performance Information:** By establishing an account, you can save and track your performance on our site. If you establish an account with us, we will collect information about your performance on our site. If you do not establish an account, we will use a session cookie to collect and track information about your performance, which is lost and unsaved upon exiting the site.

**Rostering Services Account Information:** You can also establish an account to use our site by logging in through rostering services, such as Clever, Classlink, Schoology, Microsoft, or Google Single Sign On. If you do, we may collect certain personal information through the social network, including but not limited to, your full name and email address.

**Account Information about student users in a classroom:** After a teacher/administrator has entered into an agreement with Typing.com, designated school officials can register students to use either the free or paid version. When school officials register Students, only a username and password are required, but we may collect other basic information about the students at the discretion of the school official, such as name, grade level, and class enrollment. The school official is required to obtain the consent of a parent or legal guardian of the Child before providing a Child's personal information. (Please see our "Children's Privacy Policy," below, for information about our collection and use of information from children under 13.)

**Other Information:** Regardless of whether you establish an account with us, we may collect certain information from you when you visit our Websites or use our Services so that we can maintain our Services and recognize you when you return to our Websites. In addition, the free versions contain advertising managed by Playwire LLC. Playwire LLC may collect and use certain aggregated and anonymized data for advertising purposes.

**For EU Users only:** If you are located in countries that are part of the European Economic Area, in the United Kingdom, or Switzerland, and publisher advertising services are being provided by Playwire LLC, you were presented with messaging from our Consent Management Platform (CMP) around your privacy choices as a user in regards to digital advertising, applicable vendors, cookie usage, and more.

Sharing and Use of Information
------------------------------

We use the information described above to communicate with you, manage and improve our site, and for security purposes. And, except as provided below, we will not sell, share, or disclose information we collect from or about you.

**First Party Data:** Typing.com retains data directly collected from you for education purposes only. Student names and optional email addresses are used by teachers to track student progress and manage classes.

**Google Analytics:** The free version of our site uses [Google Analytics](https://marketingplatform.google.com/about/analytics/). Google Analytics places a cookie on your web browser and collects your IP address. It does not collect names or other identifying account information. We use this information to diagnose problems and to improve and administer the site.

**Google APIs:** Typing.com's use and transfer to any other app of information received from Google APIs will adhere to [Google API Services User Data Policy](https://developers.google.com/terms/api-services-user-data-policy#additional_requirements_for_specific_api_scopes), including the Limited Use requirements.

**Stripe:** When optionally purchasing a premium version account, a payment processing software, Stripe, directly collects all personal payment information. Payment confirmation information is shared with us. We will not sell, share, or disclose this information. See the privacy policy for [Stripe](https://stripe.com/privacy) for additional information.

**Advertising:** On the free student version, Typing.com provides advertisers with aggregated, de-identified information about the user groups and usage patterns of our users. In addition, Playwire LLC may collect and use certain aggregated and anonymized data for advertising purposes. To learn more about the types of data collected, how data is used, and your choices as a user, please visit [https://www.playwire.com/privacy-policy](https://www.playwire.com/privacy-policy). When you create a paid account, your personal information will not be provided to advertisers.

**Additional Disclosures:** We will share information if required in order to comply with the law or to protect ourselves against third party claims.

Do Not Track Signals
--------------------

Like most web pages, we do not respond to Do Not Track signals.

Security
--------

No data transmission or storage over the internet is 100% secure. While we use security measures to protect your personal information, we cannot promise or guarantee absolute security.

Typing.com has adopted a cybersecurity framework to minimize the risk of data breach following [ISO 27001/27002](https://aws.amazon.com/compliance/iso-27001-faqs/). Should a security incident occur, we take the necessary steps to mitigate further security breaches. Additionally, we notify all affected parties of the incident and communication strategy for mitigating further incidents.

We operate on a principle of least privilege when determining employee data access, and databases are hosted in private networks which are inaccessible from the public internet.

Children’s Information
----------------------

Children under the age of 13 are not permitted to create their own, free student account on Typing.com without consent from a parent, legal guardian, or teacher. Children's information such as IP address, the identity of their Internet Service Provider, browser type, operating system, the site that brought them to our site, and the pages visited while on our site will still be collected, via a session cookie for performance management, from children who use the site without creating an account. This information is lost and unsaved upon exiting the site. If you are the parent, legal guardian, or teacher of someone under the age of 13 who may have created an account and provided us with information without your knowledge or consent, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.typing.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) to have this information removed. Alternatively, all created accounts can self-delete all personal information collected. To do so, login to the account page to view and delete the account, including all information collected. If you know of anyone under the age of 13 who may have provided us with information, please report it to us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.typing.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

A parent, legal guardian, or teacher may provide consent and purchase a premium student account for their child. As noted above, our teacher portal is designed for teachers that may have students that are children, and we may collect information directly from children under 13 in connection with this portion of the site. In compliance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”), see the following regarding the use of our site by children.

Children may use the student version in a classroom provided that the holder of parental responsibility over the child has provided consent and authorization, and the school has complied with its responsibilities under the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act ("FERPA") and COPPA. If a teacher or school official has consented to our collection of information from children who are students in a manner consistent with COPPA, we will collect and use such personal information. This consent can be revoked and the student’s information removed at any time. For parental and legal guardian rights, see specific section below. Contained within this privacy policy we provide each school with all the notices required under COPPA.

Please refer to the "Information We Collect" section for more information on the information we collect from children. Typing.com does not allow children to make this information publicly available.

Parent’s Rights
---------------

Parents have the right to review and request that Typing.com delete any personal information that the site has collected and retained about their child. If you would like to request that we delete any personal information we may have about your child (such as username, password, and performance information) or to request no further collection of personal information from your child, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.typing.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection), call us at [1-469-501-7758](tel:1-469-501-7758), or write to us at:

PO Box 9241  
Santurce Station,  
San Juan, Puerto Rico  
00908

Data Rights
-----------

You have the right to access, review, update, rectify, and delete any Personal Information that Typing.com holds about you or exercise any other data subject rights available to you under applicable data protection laws. In order to exercise your data subject rights, you can submit a request via email to [\[email protected\]](https://www.typing.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). Typing.com's Privacy Team will review any request and respond within a reasonable time.

Please note that we may still use any aggregated and de-identified Personal Information that does not identify any individual. Typing.com will also retain any Personal Information to the extent necessary to comply with Typing.com’s legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce Typing.com’s agreements, as outlined in this Privacy Policy.

Business Transfers
------------------

We may sell, transfer, or otherwise share some or all of our assets, including personal information, in connection with a merger, acquisition, reorganization, or sale of assets, or in the event of bankruptcy. Any such sale, transfer, or otherwise sharing of our assets shall be subject to the restrictions of this Privacy Policy and any applicable data protection laws.

Links to Other Sites
--------------------

As noted above, we use a third-party to deliver ads to our free version users. If you click on a link to a third-party site, you will be taken to websites we do not control. This policy only applies to the practices of Typing.com. We are not responsible for these third-party sites. Our site may also serve third-party content that contains their own cookies or tracking mechanisms.

International Visitors
----------------------

If you do not live in the United States, know that information we collect will be transferred to and processed in the United States. By using our site, you consent to the collection, transfer, processing, and storage of your information in the United States.

California Residents
--------------------

You have the right to request that we tell you the categories of personal information we collect about you, where we get that information from, why we collect your personal information, who we share your information with, and what pieces of information we have collected about you. You also have the right to request that we tell you the types of businesses we share your information with, and what type of personal information we share with them. You have the right to request that we delete any of your information we have collected.

You can submit any of the above requests at [\[email protected\]](https://www.typing.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). Alternatively, all created accounts can self-delete all personal information collected. To do so, login to the account page to view and delete your account, including all information collected.

We cannot discriminate against you for exercising your rights under the CCPA. Examples of discrimination would include denying you our services, charging you a different price, providing a different level of quality, or even suggesting you might receive a different price or a worse product.

California Residents – Sale of Children’s Information
-----------------------------------------------------

If you are between the ages of 13 and 16 and live in California, we cannot sell your information unless you consent. If you are a child under the age of 13, we cannot sell your information without parental consent.

If you are the parent, legal guardian, or teacher of someone under the age of 13 who may have created an account and provided us with information without your knowledge or consent, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.typing.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) to have this information removed.

Policy Changes
--------------

Typing.com may update this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any material changes to our Policy as required by law. We will also post an updated copy on our website. Please check our site periodically for updates.

Questions or Concerns
---------------------

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to email us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.typing.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or write to us at:

PO Box 9241  
Santurce Station,  
San Juan, Puerto Rico  
00908  
USA

##### Take Home Letter

Gather parental or guardian consent with this editable take-home letter.

[Download \[PDF\]](https://www.typing.com/dist/site_typing/images/resources/typingcom-take-home-agreement.pdf)

[Download \[DOCX\]](https://www.typing.com/dist/site_typing/images/resources/typingcom-take-home-agreement.docx)

Powered by:

2024 © Teaching.com

|

* 
    
    US English
    
    *  US English
        
    *  UK English
        
    *  Español
        
    *  Português

* |
    
* |
    
* |
    
* |
    
* |
